const e="crk",t=200,o=120,a=[{id:98,question:"For which of these prophets of God did the Bible record explicitly to have abandoned an agribusiness for a call to serve God? ",option:{a:"Elisha ",b:"Ezekiel ",c:"Elijah ",d:"Obadiah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:99,question:"Why did David spare the life of Saul at Ziph? ",option:{a:"he recognized Gods anointing on Saul ",b:"Saul was also an Israelite ",c:"He did not want blood shed ",d:"He was Saul’s in- law"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:100,question:"Deborah was a judge when Israel was under the yoke of ",option:{a:"Moab ",b:"Midian ",c:"Canaan ",d:"Philistine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:101,question:"The treatment of those  bitten by fiery serpent was to ",option:{a:"drink from the Red sea ",b:"look at the bronze serpent ",c:"fast for seven days ",d:"call upon the lord"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:102,question:"Which of these was detained by Joseph in order that Benjamin might be brought to Egypt ",option:{a:"Reuben ",b:"Levi ",c:"Judah ",d:"Simon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:103,question:"In the biblical account of creation, man was permitted to ",option:{a:"plant fruit trees for food ",b:"water the garden ",c:"make garment of hides and skin ",d:"name all the creatures"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:104,question:"Each of these spies sent out by Moses on God’s command to report on the nature of the promised land was a ",option:{a:"great warrior ",b:"wise judge ",c:"priest ",d:"leaders in his own tribe"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:105,question:"God reveal to Samuel that he was going to punish Eli because he ",option:{a:"did not correct his sons sinful behavior ",b:"did not offer sacrifice as the law required ",c:"did not warn the people of Israel to stop sinning ",d:"warned his sons but did not punish them"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:106,question:"The sun stood still when ",option:{a:"Moses led the Israelites out of Egypt ",b:"Jericho fell to the army of Joshua ",c:"Noah came out of the ark ",d:"Joshua defeated the Amorites at Gideon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:107,question:"When was this statement made? ‘I repent that I Made Saul king '",option:{a:"at the anointing of Saul ",b:"When Saul failed to ray ",c:"When Saul disobeyed God over Amalek ",d:"When Saul finished the morning offering"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:108,question:"The commander of David’s army was ",option:{a:"Abner ",b:"Joab ",c:"Abiathar ",d:"Adonijah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:109,question:"That was the sin of David that involved Bathseba? ",option:{a:"Murder ",b:"adultery ",c:"dishonesty ",d:"arrogance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:110,question:"What is the meaning of Emmanuel? ",option:{a:"Son of Emmaus ",b:"God is our Redeemer ",c:"God with us ",d:"Saviour"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:111,question:"What specific reply did John the Baptist give to the soldiers during his preaching ",option:{a:"collect no more than is appointed you ",b:"do not begin to say to yourselves: we have Abraham as our father ",c:"bear fruits that befit repentance ",d:"be content with your wages"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:112,question:"Jesus taught that one should make friends quickly with one’s ",option:{a:"enemy ",b:"neighbor ",c:"master ",d:"accuser"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:113,question:"The Pharisees and the Scribes accused the disciples of Jesus transgressing the tradition of the elders because they ",option:{a:"did not regard synagogue rules ",b:"did not pray before meals ",c:"ate with unwashed hands ",d:"disobeyed the elders"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:114,question:"If anyone would be first, he must be last of all and servant of all. What does this saying of Jesus teach? ",option:{a:"endurance ",b:"lack of ambition ",c:"humility ",d:"relaxation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:115,question:"Which religious groups asked Jesus about payment of taxes to Ceaser? ",option:{a:"Pharisees and Sadducces ",b:"Pharisees and Herodians ",c:"Sadducces and herodians ",d:"Herodians and Zealots"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:116,question:"To whom was the body of Jesus Christ given for burial after His death? ",option:{a:"Nicodemus the Pharisee ",b:"Simon of Cyrene ",c:"Simon the disciple ",d:"Joseph of Arimathea."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:117,question:"Paul was accused of apparently being a preacher of foreign divinities in Athens because he preached Jesus and the ",option:{a:"Cross ",b:"Law ",c:"resurrection ",d:"second coming"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:118,question:"What specifically makes Samson a unique prophet of God? ",option:{a:"He was a Nazarene ",b:"He loved honey ",c:"He killed many at his death ",d:"He spoke with power in riddles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:119,question:"“It is not the sound of shouting for victory, or the sound of the cry of defeat, but the sound of singing that I hear” When was this statement made? ",option:{a:"at the consecration of the Israelites ",b:"at the crossing of the Red Sea ",c:"during the fall of Jericho ",d:"in a strange worship of a god"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:120,question:"“Blessed be the Lord God of Israel is a hymn of praise by ",option:{a:"the virgin Mary at the Annunciation ",b:"Zachariah at the birth of John the Baptist ",c:"Simeon at the presentation of Jesus in the temple ",d:"Elizabeth at the visit of Mary"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:121,question:"The shema emphasizes the ",option:{a:"unity of God ",b:"richness of the spirit of God ",c:"omnipotence of God ",d:"crucial role o’ Israel in the world."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:122,question:"The expression ‘dry bones’ in Ezekiel refers to ",option:{a:"an Israelites proverb ",b:"the whole house of Israel ",c:"the slain in the valley ",d:"sinful Israelites and Judean"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:546,question:"On the fourth day, God created the sun, moon and stars for the following purposes except",option:{a:"to separate the day from the night.",b:"for signs of seasons, days and years.",c:"to give light upon the earth.",d:"to dry up flood from the face of the earth."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:547,question:"Which of the following rivers flowed out of Eden to water 	its garden? River",option:{a:"Abana",b:"Pharpar",c:"Pishon",d:"Nile"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:548,question:"The wife of Moses was called",option:{a:"Rebecca.",b:"Rachel.",c:"Zipporah.",d:"Deborah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:549,question:"When Joseph was sent to his brothers, he met them pasturing at",option:{a:"Hebron.",b:"Bethel.",c:"Beersheba",d:"Dothan"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:550,question:"How old was Joshua before he died?",option:{a:"95 years",b:"98 years",c:"110 years",d:"111 years"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:551,question:"Why was Saul asked to destroy the Amalekites?",option:{a:"They were worshipping false gods",b:"They opposed the Israelites when they left Egypt",c:"They did not assist the Israelites",d:"God did not like the Amalekites"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:552,question:"The first king of Israel lost his throne because he",option:{a:"was a weak king.",b:"knew little about governance.",c:"lost the support of Yahweh.",d:"was irresponsible."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:553,question:"During the Ammonite war Uriah disobeyed King David by refusing to go to his house to sleep because",option:{a:"it was wrong to go home drunk.",b:"his wife would regard him as a coward.",c:"it would be unpatriotic to break military vow.",d:"he suspected that the king had lost interest in the battle."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:554,question:"When Abner wanted to transfer his allegiance to David, the latter gave him the condition to",option:{a:"openly submit to Joab.",b:"convince all Israel to come over to David.",c:"restore his wife Michal to him.",d:"slay Ishbosheth. Saul’s successor."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:555,question:"God said to Solomon in a dream, <em>“Ask what I shall give you”</em>. What did Solomon ask for?",option:{a:"Power and authority",b:"Great wealth and riches",c:"Stable and long term in office",d:"An understanding mind"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:556,question:"Solomon showed lack of wisdom when he",option:{a:"put up temples for the gods of his wives",b:"married many wives with children",c:"invited the Queen of Sheba",d:"gave out judgment to two harlots."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:557,question:"Solomon told Hiram, King of Tyre that he had decided to build a temple for the Lord because",option:{a:"the Lord had given him peace and all good things.",b:"his father, David, never intended to build one.",c:"he wanted to force Hiram to come to his aid.",d:"Hiram had entered into a marriage alliance with his father."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:558,question:"Elijah destroyed the prophets of Baal",option:{a:"to oppose Baal worship.",b:"as an act of revenge.",c:"as an act of sacrifice.",d:"to shame Jezebel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:559,question:"Who was the king who reintroduced the Passover feast in Israel?",option:{a:"Jeroboam",b:"Asa",c:"Josiah",d:"Rehoboam"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:560,question:"Who was the prophet responsible for the re-building of the Temple during the exile?",option:{a:"Ezra",b:"Isaiah",c:"Jeremiah",d:"Ezekiel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:561,question:"Which of the following prophets taught that Yahweh was merciful?",option:{a:"Isaiah",b:"Hosea",c:"Amos",d:"Ezekiel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:562,question:"Daniel was delivered from the lion’s den because",option:{a:"of his faith in God’s power.",b:"of the king’s prayers.",c:"he was able to charm the lions.",d:"the lions were kind to him."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:563,question:"The person who discovered the book of law in the sanctuary during the reign of Josiah was",option:{a:"Zedekiah",b:"Huldah.",c:"Hilkiah",d:"Jeremiah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:564,question:"According to Amos’ prophecy, the “Day of the Lord” to the Israelites would be a day of",option:{a:"victory over enemies",b:"happiness.",c:"doom.",d:"national triumph."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:565,question:"Isaiah said that when Israel spread forth their hands, God would hide his face because they were",option:{a:"making many prayers",b:"offering vain sacrifices.",c:"worshipping God with their hearts.",d:"observing elaborate feasts."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:566,question:"From Luke’s account of the baptism of Jesus, which of the following happened before the voice was heard?",option:{a:"John was reluctant to baptize Him.",b:"John called Jesus the Lamb of God.",c:"Jesus arrived with Peter, James and John",d:"The Holy Spirit descended upon Jesus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:567,question:"Before their first encounter with Jesus, Peter and Andrew were",option:{a:"preachers.",b:"tax collectors.",c:"fishermen.",d:"tent makers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:568,question:"By the action of the Good Samaritan, Christians are encouraged to",option:{a:"go out to the streets and look for someone to help.",b:"always travel with enough money in case the need arises to help.",c:"show compassion and render help to the needy.",d:"avoid travelling on lonely roads where armed robbers could attack."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:569,question:"The <em>lost sheep</em> and the <em>lost coin</em> share the following except that",option:{a:"both of them are lost and need to be found",b:"it is their owners’ responsibility to look for them.",c:"the coin, may not know that it is lost.",d:"their owners rejoice when they are found."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:570,question:"The parable of the rich man and Lazarus indicates that",option:{a:"poverty is a mark of righteousness.",b:"death is a leveler for rich and poor",c:"only poor people will die physically.",d:"all rich men are going to hell fire."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:571,question:"In one of the resurrection appearances Jesus asked his disciples, whether they had anything to eat as he",option:{a:"was hungry after three days in the grave without food.",b:"suspected that the disciples stock may have finished",c:"wanted to prove to them that he was not a ghost.",d:"wanted to replenish the food stuff."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:572,question:"By introducing Jesus as the Lamb, John was pointing to",option:{a:"Jesus’ sacrificial death.",b:"Jesus’ miraculous healing.",c:"the Jewish yearly sacrifices.",d:"the priestly function of Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:573,question:"St. John refers to Jesus’ miracles as ‘signs’ because they convey the following ideas except",option:{a:"acceptance of Jesus as son of God.",b:"proofs of the kingdom of God.",c:"faith in Jesus as the means to eternal life.",d:"demand for more wonders."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:574,question:"Apart from the miracles at the wedding feast, another miracle of Jesus at Cana in Galilee was",option:{a:"feeding the four thousand.",b:"healing the noble man’s son.",c:"healing of a man born blind",d:"healing a paralytic man."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:575,question:"At whose well did Jesus meet the Samaritan woman?",option:{a:"Abraham",b:"Isaac",c:"Jacob",d:"Joseph"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:576,question:"The lame man who was healed at the pool of Bethizatha was charged by the Jews for breaking the law of the Sabbath 	because he",option:{a:"consulted Jesus on the Sabbath day.",b:"was carrying his pallet on a Sabbath day.",c:"was on a journey on a Sabbath day.",d:"was seen with Jesus on a Sabbath day."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:577,question:"The descent of the Holy Spirit on the day of  Pentecost was prophesied by",option:{a:"Amos.",b:"Joel.",c:"David.",d:"Ezekiel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:578,question:"When the apostles in Jerusalem heard that Samaria had received the gospel, they sent to them",option:{a:"Mark and Barnabas.",b:"Peter and John.",c:"Paul and John.",d:"Peter and Paul."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:579,question:"The conversion of the Ethiopian eunuch confirms the",option:{a:"universality of the gospel.",b:"work of the Apostles.",c:"work of Philip in Samaria",d:"the love of God for the eunuch."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:580,question:"After his conversion, Paul was introduced to the disciples in Jerusalem by",option:{a:"Peter",b:"Ananias.",c:"Barnabas.",d:"Philip"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:581,question:"Before Barnabas and Saul were sent on missionary journey, the elders, laid hands on them. The laying on of  hands signifies",option:{a:"confirmation.",b:"selection.",c:"commissioning.",d:"protection"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:582,question:"The man who delivered judgment of the Jerusalem Council on the admission of Gentiles into the Church was",option:{a:"Peter.",b:"Paul.",c:"Barnabas.",d:"James."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:583,question:"Why according to Paul must Christians be subject to civil authority?",option:{a:"To receive God’s approval",b:"To avoid God’s wrath",c:"God has commanded it",d:"It is an Old Testament law"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:584,question:"In the Epistle to the Romans, justification is received through",option:{a:"faith in Jesus.",b:"moral uprightness",c:"observance of the law.",d:"giving of alms"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:585,question:"By saying that no human being will be justified in the sight of God by works: Paul meant that",option:{a:"the mosaic law was useless in ensuring justification for man.",b:"the law had been weakened in human flesh.",c:"knowledge of sin came through the law.",d:"Moses who gave the law was not justified by the law."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:586,question:"Paul’s greatest writing about spiritual gift is found in his letter to the",option:{a:"Galatians.",b:"Ephesians.",c:"Romans.",d:"Corinthians"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:587,question:"In Corinthians, Paul cited all the following resurrection appearances of Jesus except",option:{a:"Cephas.",b:"The Twelve.",c:"Mary Magdalene",d:"James."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:588,question:"According to Peter, a Christian should exercise his freedom by",option:{a:"doing what is right.",b:"claiming his freedom at all cost.",c:"enduring pain while suffering.",d:"using it as a pretext for evil."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:589,question:"In which of the following ways did the Philippians share in Paul’s suffering while in prison?",option:{a:"Appealing for the release of Paul",b:"Sending him relief materials",c:"Continuing in prayer for him",d:"Remaining in partnership with him in receiving."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:590,question:"What advice did Peter give to the elders of the church in their relationship with the younger members?",option:{a:"Work as if being under external constraint",b:"Work without a domineering spirit",c:"Work with a desire for material gains",d:"Control their flocks with firm hands"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:591,question:"In Philippians, Paul taught that Jesus ‘humility and death on the cross earned Him",option:{a:"salvation for Israel.",b:"adoption as son of God.",c:"exaltation as Lord.",d:"eternal life in the kingdom."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:592,question:"Why did Paul wish to retain Onesimus?",option:{a:"To protect him from persecution",b:"Christianity was opposed to slavery",c:"Philemon had earnestly requested that from Paul",d:"To serve him during his imprisonment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:593,question:"James teaches that the man who shall be blessed is he who",option:{a:"hears the word of God.",b:"knows the law perfectly.",c:"does the word he hears.",d:"teaches the word of God well."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:594,question:"Through God the Christian is no longer a slave but a son, and if a son then",option:{a:"a master.",b:"a redeemed.",c:"an heir.",d:"a beneficiary."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:595,question:"Peter recommends submission to the civil authority so as to",option:{a:"silence the ungodly.",b:"encourage the believers.",c:"promote faith in God.",d:"live as free men."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:596,question:"What was God’s purpose in creating man?",option:{a:"To be master of all creation",b:"To help Him look after the garden",c:"To name the things He created",d:"To multiply and fill the earth"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:597,question:"Isaac’s prayer to God for his barren wife showed that he",option:{a:"truly loved her",b:"sincerely loved his God",c:"had faith in God",d:"was tired of being childless"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:598,question:"In God’s covenant with Israel, the central theme was",option:{a:"restoration",b:"circumcision",c:"obedience",d:"salvation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:599,question:"‘Who am I that I should go to Pharoah......’ When Moses resisted God’s call with the state¬ment above, it portrayed his",option:{a:"stubbornness",b:"incompetence",c:"lack of strength",d:"lack of eloquence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:600,question:"What was Samson’s major achievement as Israel’s leader?",option:{a:"He suppressed the Philistines",b:"He captured the city of Jericho",c:"He saved the Israelites from the Amorites",d:"He secured permanent independence for Israel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:601,question:"God guided the Israelites on their way from Egypt to the Promised Land by",option:{a:"the work of two angels",b:"dividing the Red Sea",c:"a pillar of cloud and a pillar of fire",d:"miracles that gave them direction on the way"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:602,question:"‘Deal gently for my sake with the young man Absalom.’ David’s statement above exhibited his",option:{a:"indulgent love for his son",b:"willingness to forgive his competitors",c:"desire to punish Absalom himself",d:"high level of parental control"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:603,question:"How did king Asa prove to be a godly king?",option:{a:"He killed all the prophets of Baal at Mount Carmel.",b:"He saved Judah from the Philistine menace",c:"He instituted spiritual reforms that removed all idols and prostitution in the land.",d:"He made the worship of Yahweh mandatory for every Jew and sojourner."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:604,question:"The Hebrew midwives who obeyed God rather than Pharaoh were blessed with",option:{a:"favour from all the Israelites",b:"long life in Canaan",c:"resources",d:"families"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:605,question:"When Saul disobeyed God’s command, Samuel rebuked him by saying that",option:{a:"the sword would never depart from his house",b:"to obey was better than sacrifice",c:"he should fear the LORD and obey the people’s voice.",d:"though he was little, yet he was the head."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:606,question:"David’s behaviour after Prophet Nathan accused him of murder and adultery showed his",option:{a:"justification",b:"repentance",c:"greed",d:"righteousness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:607,question:`How did King Solomon demonstrate his wisdom in settling the dispute over the ownership of a baby by the two 
Prostitutes?`,option:{a:"He interrogated them for seven days until the truth was discovered.",b:"He interrogated them for only three days and the truth was revealed",c:"He asked them to divide the child into two and the mother was known.",d:"He threatened to give the child to a neutral woman and the mother was known."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:608,question:"The prophet who made known the imminent divi¬sion of the kingdom of Israel during Solomon’s reign was",option:{a:"Jehu",b:"Ahijah",c:"Elisha",d:"Elijah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:609,question:"Naaman’s leprosy was transferred to Gehazi be¬cause Gehazi was",option:{a:"ambitious",b:"anxious",c:"covetous",d:"contemptuous"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:610,question:"Obadiah who was m charge of Ahab’s house hold demonstrated reverence for the LORD by",option:{a:"giving Elijah the bull for the sacrifice on Mount Carmel.",b:"rebuking Ahab and Jezebel for their evil deeds",c:"hiding a hundred prophets of God from Jezebel’s wrath.",d:"helping Elijah to kill the prophets of Baal on Mount Carmel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:611,question:"Although Josiah removed the vessels of Baal and Asherah from the Temple, God did not turn from the fierceness of His 	wrath because”",option:{a:"the people did not remove them completely",b:"Jehoahaz, Josiah’s son, had provoked Him",c:"Manasseh had provoked Him",d:"the people had opposed Josiah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:612,question:"What was Nehemiah’s initial reaction to the news about the ruins of Jerusalem?",option:{a:"He tasked the people on what to contribute",b:"He called for volunteers to assist him",c:"He fasted and prayed for forgiveness of sins",d:"He asked for permission to travel home."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:613,question:"After the dedication of the Temple, Ezra studied the law of the LORD in order to",option:{a:"defend the Jews against the Babylonians",b:"become the first judge in Jerusalem",c:"enhance his prophetic status",d:"teach His statutes and ordinances in Israel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:614,question:"Daniel became distinguished above all other pre¬sidents and satraps because",option:{a:"an excellent spirit was in him",b:"the spirit of Darius was in him",c:"he was a good administrator",d:"he was highly educated."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:615,question:"How did the Ninevites react to Jonah’s message?",option:{a:"They did not believe it",b:"They believed it for a while",c:"They repented of their sins",d:"They ordered him out of their city"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:616,question:"In Prophet Hosea’s analysis, harlotry is equivalent to Israel’s",option:{a:"prostitution",b:"idolatrous practices",c:"religious practices",d:"adultery."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:617,question:"‘... But let justice roll down like waters, and righteousness like an overflowing stream.’ Amos’ statement above suggests that the society was terribly",option:{a:"vindictive",b:"abusive",c:"oppressive",d:"destructive"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:618,question:"Isaiah emphasized holiness above all things be¬cause God",option:{a:"knew their hearts were right with him",b:"was not interested in their sacrifices",c:"who called them is holy",d:"was searching their sinful   hearts."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:619,question:"God told Ezekiel that the house of Israel would not listen to him because they",option:{a:"were a people of foreign speech",b:"had forsaken His laws",c:"were of a stubborn heart",d:"had not truly repented"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:620,question:"According to Isaiah, God sent him to",option:{a:"proclaim liberty to the captives",b:"proclaim victory over Israel’s enemies",c:"be a watchman over Israel",d:"destroy and overthrow nations."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:621,question:"Jesus was tempted by the devil so as to",option:{a:"fulfil all righteousness",b:"show His power over forces of nature",c:"show that no one is above temptation",d:"test the devil’s power"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:622,question:"‘Depart from me, for l am a sinful man, oh Lord.’ This statement was uttered by Peter at the",option:{a:"last supper",b:"garden of Gethsemane",c:"call of the disciples",d:"transfiguration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:623,question:"The impact of Jesus’ miracle of turning water into wine was that the",option:{a:"servants were astonished",b:"master of ceremony believed",c:"disciples believed more in Him",d:"people glorified God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:624,question:"After the healing of the demoniac in the country of the Gerasenes, the people begged Jesus to (Mark 5:15-19)",option:{a:"stay with them",b:"visit them always",c:"go away from them",d:"heal their sick."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:625,question:"Jesus told the parable of the lost sheep in order to illustrate that",option:{a:"every believer ought to rejoice with those who rejoice.",b:"no person can hide from God",c:"God’s love is unlimited",d:"there is joy in heaven over a sinner who repents"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:626,question:"According to Jesus, the seventy disciples should rejoice because",option:{a:"their names were written in heaven",b:"their faith and zeal were increased",c:"of the submission of evil Spirits to them",d:"of the fall of Satan from heaven like lightening."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:627,question:"According to Mark, after the transfiguration, Jesus charged His disciples to",option:{a:"be prepared for persecution",b:"tell no one what they had seen",c:"have no hands in His betrayal",d:"go to the Gentiles immediately"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:628,question:"According to Luke, the multitude that followed Jesus during the triumphal entry rejoiced and praised God with a loud voice because (Luke 19:37-39)",option:{a:"they realized that Jesus was a prophet",b:"of the mighty works He had done",c:"He was riding on a colt in humility",d:"they believed He was their Messiah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:629,question:"‘Truly, I say to you, today you will be with me in paradise.....’ Jesus made the statement above to one of the 		criminals because he (Luke 23:42-43)",option:{a:"respected Him",b:"praised Him",c:"rebuked his partner",d:"was repentant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:630,question:"The message of the risen Christ to the women who came early to the tomb was to be relayed to the disciples and (Mark 16:7)",option:{a:"the Jews",b:"the Sadducees",c:"Thomas",d:"Peter"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:631,question:"According to the Gospel of John, Jesus is the true vine while the vinedresser is (John 15:1)",option:{a:"the Holy Spirit",b:"His father",c:"the gardener",d:"His mother"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:632,question:"‘...Why has Satan filled your heart to lie to the Holy Spirit..’ Peter rebuked Ananias in the statement above for his sin of (Acts 5:3-4)",option:{a:"greed",b:"insincerity",c:"covetousness",d:"partiality."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:633,question:"Paul informed the Galatians that the gospel he preached came through (Gal. 3:23-29)",option:{a:"a revelation of Jesus Christ",b:"his desire to lead them",c:"inspiration from the angels",d:"the faith of men."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:634,question:"‘You son of the devil, you enemy of all righteous¬ness, full of all deceit and villainy .....’ This statement of Paul was addressed to (Acts 13:6-11)",option:{a:"Elymas, the magician",b:"Paulus, the proconsul",c:"Simon, the Magician",d:"Demetrius, the silversmith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:635,question:"‘Unless you are circumcised according to the custom of Moses, you cannot be saved.’ The statement above by the men from Judea led to the",option:{a:"murmurs of the Hellenists",b:"convening of the Jerusalem Council",c:"persecution that scattered the disciples",d:"circumcision of the Gentiles."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:636,question:"According to Galatians, the Law was added be¬cause of",option:{a:"righteousness",b:"transgressions",c:"grace",d:"persecution."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:637,question:"According to Galatians, the death of Christ has eliminate all forms of",option:{a:"suffering",b:"differences",c:"condemnation",d:"poverty."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:638,question:"Peter in his teaching no humility, admonishes Christians to",option:{a:"safeguard their faith",b:"seek things that are above",c:"be gentle in spirit",d:"avoid life’s anxiety"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:639,question:"Paul in Corinthians advised that Christians should re-affirm their love for those who",option:{a:"are kind to them",b:"wrong them",c:"humble themselves",d:"are in authority."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:640,question:"According to Corinthians, variety of gifts are inspired by",option:{a:"fervent prayers",b:"angels of God",c:"constant fasting",d:"the same Spirit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"}],i={subject:e,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,i as default,t as status,e as subject,o as total};
